(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T13:40:08.675770",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな、こんばんはー！
Everyone, good evening!
お待たせー！
Thanks for waiting!
どうもホロライブの
Hello, Hololive stream start!
配信スタート、みんな泣いてる、夏色、まつりだー！
Everyone's crying, it's Natsuiro Matsuri!
イエイイエイ！こんばんは！みんな元気してる？
Yay yay! Good evening! Is everyone doing well?
元気してますかね？元気そうだね、よかった！
Are you doing well? You look well, that's great!
ということで本日は、今日何の日か知ってますか？今日何の配信か知ってる？
So today, do you know what day it is today? Do you know what kind of stream today is?
そう、サムネイルにもある通り、今日は夏色まつりの50万人の配信だー！いぇい、いぇい！
That's right, today is Natsuiro Matsuri's 500k subscriber stream! Yay, yay!
ということでね、本日は皆さんお集まりいただきありがとうございます。
So, thank you all so much for gathering here today.
もうすでにチャンネル登録は50万人を越え
Channel subscriptions have already exceeded 500k,
ちょっと今何人か分かんないですけど、52、2とかだったかな？
I'm not sure how many it is right now, but maybe 522k or something?
だたと思う、ありがとうございます。いやね、ありがたいね、ありがとうございますね。
I think so, thank you. Man, I'm so grateful, thank you.
本当に、いや50万人ってさ、やばくないだってみんな。
Really, I mean 500k, isn't that crazy?
金たてまであと、あれよ、半分よ？
Just halfway to the Gold button, you know?
もう一回同じことすればもう、もう金たてだからね！
If I do the exact same thing again, it'll be the Gold button!
強しじゃん。あれ？もう53人いとる（笑）
That's strong. Huh? We already have 530k!
ちょ、早すぎなんよ！みんな、早すぎます。
Wait, that's too fast! Everyone, you're way too fast.
そう、登録ありがと！そしてスーパーチャットも本日はありがとうございます、50万人に改めてありがとね、ありがとうございますよ。
Right, thanks for subscribing! And thank you for the Super Chats today too.
いやなんかね、台本に50万人を迎えた瞬間泣きましたって、あ、泣きましたじゃない、何してました？
Man, like, in the script it says 'I cried the moment I reached 500k', ah, not I cried, what was I doing?
何してました？まつりさ、あれだよね、あれしてたよね、配信してたよね？
What was I doing? Matsuri, you know, I was doing that right? I was streaming, right?
あれ？してたっけ？50万人迎えたい配信みたいな、やってた気がするわ。
Huh? Was I? I feel like I was doing a 'wanting to reach 500k' kind of stream.
で、あの、あれやってんだよ。1万人と2000、あるぞ？1万人と2000年前から？
And, um, I was doing that thing. 10k and 2k... is there? From 10k and 2k years ago?
おれ、もー！ってやってたわ。覚えてた、覚えてた、歌ってたね、懐かしいね。
'Ore, moo!' I used to do that. I remembered, I remembered, I used to sing that, how nostalgic.
懐かしい、もうすでに懐かしい気するも。あれが半月前くらいですか？
Nostalgic, it already feels nostalgic. Was that about half a month ago?
半月前？半月前、半月前くらいから2週間前くらいだよね？あれ？その間にはまつり3万人増えてんの？
Half a month ago? About half a month, two weeks ago right? Huh? In that time, Matsuri gained 30k people?
やばくない！？いやこれがね、でもなんか
Isn't that crazy!? Man, but you know,
いや、これってなんかまつりの力っていうかあれですよね、まつりしがさ、いっぱいツイートしてくれたりとかさ
Well, this is kind of Matsuri's power, or rather, Matsurishi tweeting a lot and stuff,
そして広めてくれたりとか、あとホロライブ全体がさ、こう盛り上がってってんなーって思わない？思うんですよ、だからみんなありがとうございます。
and spreading the word, and don't you think Hololive as a whole is getting so hyped up? I think so, so everyone thank you very much.
ホロライブをよろしくお願いします！そして今日もね
Please support Hololive! And today too,
あの、もうすでにツイートしてくれてる方はわかると思うけど、こちらの夏色まつり3Dっていうね、ハッシュタグとね、あと概要欄の、あの下のこの辺から
um, those who have already tweeted probably know, but this hashtag 'NatsuiroMatsuri3D' and, um, from around the bottom of the description box here
あるさ、URLとかをコピーしてさ、ツイートしてくれたら喜ぶ、まつりが嬉しいので共有して行ってください。
if you copy the URL and tweet it, I'll be happy, Matsuri will be happy, so please share it.
シェアハピしてください。よろしくね！ということで、えっと、今後の目標を教えてくださいって書いてある。
Share happy please. See you! So, um, it says 'Please tell us your future goals.'
本日の目標はね、
Today's goal is,
登録者数100万人ですね！100万人！
1 million subscribers! 1 million!
100万人いったら、あのマネージャーに焼肉をご馳走してもらう。
If we hit 1 million, I'll have the manager treat me to yakiniku.
いいよね、連れ添いたぶんしてくれると思うんで、
That sounds good, they'll probably accommodate me, so
あのマネージャーに焼肉をご馳走してもらいたいので、
I want the manager to treat me to yakiniku,
あの、金盾、金盾を目指して頑張ります。
um, aiming for a Gold Shield, I'll do my best.
いや、焼肉をご馳走されたいじゃん。
I mean, wouldn't you want to be treated to yakiniku?
牛角でいい。牛角か、あの、あそこでいい、あの、なんだら太郎、スタミナ太郎！
Gyu-Kaku is fine. Or Gyu-Kaku, or, you know, Stamina Taro!
スタミナ太郎、い、いか、行かせてくれ！頼む！マネージャー待ってるよ、よろしくね！
Stamina Taro, please let me go! I'm begging you! Manager, I'm waiting, please!
というわけでね、今日は、まあ、あの、大好きなホロライブメンバーがクイズを、クイズを出してくれてね、それに答えたりとか、
So, today, well, um, my beloved Hololive members gave us a quiz, and we'll answer it,
まあ、祭りっこと一緒にひと夏の思い出、もう夏が終わりますけれども、ひと夏の最後の思い出を作れる企画やらね。
and well, making the final memories of summer with Matsuri-ko, even though summer is ending, some kind of project to create our final summer memories.
あと最後にはね、ちょっとだけ歌っちゃったりなんかしたりしちゃったりなんちゃらっちゃらなので、よろしくお願いしますよ！最後まで見守ってくれよな！
And lastly, we'll sing a little bit and do various things, so please look forward to it! Make sure to watch until the end!
というわけで、さっそくですが最初のコーナーに、
So, without further ado, for our first corner,
レッツラゴー！
Let's go!
４択まつり！
4-Choice Matsuri!
さてさて、4択クイズのお時間です。
Now then, it's time for the 4-choice quiz.
みんな4択クイズは得意ですかね？まあ4択だからね、簡単ですよ。
Is everyone good at 4-choice quizzes? Well, it's 4-choice, so it's easy.
ルール説明：今からホロライブメンバーからクイズが出題されます。4択で出題されるので正解だと思うものを選んでください。
Rule explanation: A quiz will now be given by Hololive members. Since it's a 4-choice quiz, please choose what you think is the correct answer.
なるほどね。まあまあまあ、ホロライブメンバー仲いいからさ、余裕だよ。ていうか協力してくれたホロライブメンバーありがとうございます！サンクス！
I see. Well, Hololive members get along well, so it's a breeze. Also, thank you to the Hololive members who cooperated! Thanks!
ということで、まあ、あの机があってさ、邪魔だから、これをちょっとね、あの、ちょっと退けたいと思います。
So, well, um, there's a desk and it's in the way, so I'd like to move it out of the way a bit.
いでよ！あ、もう出てる！エビフライよ！
Come forth! Oh, it's already here! Shrimp tempura!
出てきた！これで綺麗にしますね。
It came out! We'll clean up with this.
この机邪魔なんで、ちょっと痛いかもよ、エビフライよ。いい？いくよ！
Since this desk is in the way, Shrimp Tempura, it might hurt a bit. Ready? Here we go!
おら！
Take this!
どけ！どけお前ら！机邪魔なんだよ！消え失せろ！おら！おらおらおらおらおら！おっけ！おっけ！ありがと、エビフライよ！
Move! Move out of the way, you guys! The desks are in the way! Disappear! Take this! Take that! Okay! Okay! Thanks, Shrimp Tempura!
じゃあ、君の仕事はこれで終わりなんだ。さようなら。
Well, your job is done with this. Goodbye.
これだけの為に今年は出演していただきました、エビフライよにはね、もう出てきません。
You only appeared today for this, Shrimp Tempura won't be coming out anymore.
もうこの後1回も出てこないんでね。すみません、エビフライよさん、ありがとうございました。
They won't appear even once after this. Sorry, Shrimp Tempura-san, thank you very much.
ということで、さっそくですが、えっと、出していきましょう！4択パネル！お、カモン！
So, without further ado, let's put it out! 4-Choice Panel! Oh, come on!
はい、出た！うわ、問題も一緒に出てきました。
Yes, it's out! Wow, the question came out too.
消した。
I deleted it.
いやいや、何も見てないね、みんな今ね。何も見てない。
No, no, nobody's looking at anything right now. Nobody's looking.
それじゃあ、さっそく行きましょうか！
Then let's get right to it!
第1問！お願いします！だだーん！
Question 1! Please! Ta-da!
はい、出ないんかい！
Hey, it doesn't come out!
こっちでは出ないんだ。あ、出たね。出たね。
It doesn't come out here. Ah, it came out. It came out.
えー、まつりちゃ先輩がルーナとコラボ中に初めて泣いたのは何の配信なのだ？
Uh, on what stream did Matsuri-cha-senpai cry for the first time during a collab with Luna?
これ、ルーナからの問題です。ルーナ、ありがとう！
This is a question from Luna. Luna, thank you!
で、これね、簡単だよね。
And, you know, this is easy.
え、赤が「世界のアソビ大全51」の配信。
Uh, red is \"Clubhouse Games: 51 Worldwide Classics\" stream.
そして、緑が「マインクラフト」の配信。
And green is \"Minecraft\" stream.
青が「夏色まつり誕生日祭2020」の配信。
Blue is \"Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Festival 2020\" stream.
そして「姫森ルーナ3Dお披露目配信」。
And \"Himemori Luna 3D Reveal Stream\".
ちなみに、まつりあの、この配信の中で3つは泣いてるんですよ。3つは。
By the way, Matsuri, in this stream, cried in three of these. Three of them.
3つは泣いてる。で、「世界のアソビ大全」は泣いてないんですよ。ボロボロにあの、オセロでね、あの、まつりが白でルーナが黒だったんだけど、全部黒になっちゃったんだけど、
Three of them she cried. And she didn't cry in \"Clubhouse Games\". In Othello, I was white and Luna was black, and it all turned black,
まあ、泣いてないですよ。
well, she didn't cry.
そして「マイクラ」は泣いた。泣いたんです。もう大号泣。大変。
And in \"Minecraft\" she cried. She cried. Total crying. Terrible.
マイクラでなんで泣いたかは、まあ、アーカイブも見てくださいっていう感じなんですけど。
Why she cried in Minecraft, well, please check the archive.
「夏色まつり誕生日祭」も泣きました。これもう、まさかまさかのサプライズで号泣させられた。
\"Natsuiro Matsuri Birthday Festival\" she also cried too. This one made me cry in total surprise.
で、ルーナのお披露目配信は、配信内では泣いてないけど、
And Luna's reveal stream, she didn't cry during the stream, but
ルーナが一番最初にさ、歌ってさ、始まったときに、「あ、ルーナが歌って楽しそうにしとるわ」と思ったら、待機してたんだけどうらで、泣きましたね、それは。うん。
when Luna started singing at the very first, I thought, \"Ah, Luna is singing and looking happy,\" but she was waiting behind the scenes, and I cried, yeah.
それは泣いた。
That made me cry.
で、まあ答えを言ってしまうと、めっ ちゃ簡単。
And, well, if I give you the answer, it's super easy.
「マインクラフト」ですね。「マインクラフト」が一番最初に泣きました。
It's \"Minecraft\". \"Minecraft\" is where she cried first.
じゃあ説明は追々ということで、まず答えを見てみましょう。あ、待って。
Then explanations will come later, first let's see the answer. Ah, wait.
じゃ、そんなことないな。
"Well, that's not it."
じゃあいこうか。マインクラフトだと思います。
"So let's go with Minecraft."
正解はこちら！
"The correct answer is right here!"
正解！よかった、よかった。
"Correct! Yay, I'm so glad."
そう、マインクラフト配信で泣いたんですよ。
"That's right, I cried during a Minecraft stream."
あのね、これね、
"You see, this..."
ルーナの3Dお披露目の前かな？のときに、
"...was right before Luna's 3D debut showcase, I think?"
祭りがなんかね、誕生日前かな？
"Matsuri was, you know, right before her birthday, I guess?"
なんかね、祭りに嬉しかったよ、ルーナに出会えて。
"Matsuri was so happy to meet Luna, you know."
で、なんか感激おまっしちゃって泣いたの、覚えてます。
"And then, I was so moved that I started crying, I remember that."
はい、正解！ルーナの前夜祭か。前夜、前夜にマイクラ一緒にやって、
"Yes, that's right! Luna's eve. The night before, we played Minecraft together,"
ガチ泣きしたルーナに出会えてよかった。
"and I cried for real because I was so glad to meet Luna."
だめヘラみたいですね。
"I sound like a total mental mess."
あ、ちなみにこれ全問正解すると、特にご褒美ありませんって言われたんだけど、
"Oh, by the way, if I get all questions right, they told me there are no special rewards, but..."
あの、祭り権限で配信外でね、今日ディレクターがいるんですよ。ディレクターが土下座してくれるって
"you know, using my Matsuri authority off-stream, there's a director here today. The director said they'd dogeza for me"
いうのをね、取り付けてみました。配信外で土下座させるために、
"so I managed to arrange that. To make them dogeza off-stream,"
あの、がんばりま、その屈辱を味わってほしいんですよ、
"um, I'll do my best—I want them to experience that humiliation,"
ディレクターにね。じゃあやっていきましょうか。
"Mr. Director. So let's keep going."
ホロライブ闇企業って言われるわ、これ。
"People are gonna call Hololive a black company for this."
じゃあ、第1問は正解！
"So, Question 1 was correct!"
じゃあ続いて第2問！ででん！
"Then, moving on to Question 2! Ta-da!"
え、星街すいせいのMUSIC SPACEに祭りちゃんがゲスト出演した時、三曲デュエットしました。その際に歌った曲はどれでしょう？
"Uh, when Matsuri-chan was a guest on Hoshimachi Suisei's MUSIC SPACE, you did a three-song duet. Which song did you sing then?"
すいすいからの問題です。
"This is a question from Suisei."
もうこんなん簡単じゃん。
"This is way too easy."
これ、1問目なんてもの？ネクスト、コロル、こ、こ、コロ、プラネット。あ、ネクストコメプラネットね。
"This, what's question 1? Next... Color... Pl... Planet. Ah, Next Color Planet, right?"
あのさ、一瞬さ、あの、コールって言っちゃったし、普通に間違えたし。
"You know, for a second, I said 'call' and totally messed it up."
からね？カラードプラネットね。
"From... Colorful Planet, right?"
英語だと読めないやつね、あの、すいすいの曲ね。うん。
"The ones I can't read in English, you know, Suisei's songs. Yeah."
英語弱い弱い人間すぎるからさ、あの、読み仮名を振ってほしい。うん、読み仮名をね、すいすいのオリジナル曲ですね。
"I'm way too bad at English, so I want you to put furigana for me. Yeah, furigana for Suisei's original songs."
と、あと、「変わらないもの」「君の知らない物語」優しいさに包まれたならですね。
"And, 'Kawaranai Mono', 'Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari', and 'Yasashisa ni Tsutsumareta Nara'."
あの、ネクストさ、カラープラネットさ、祭りさ、あれだよ、コール入ったよ、入ってたよね？
"Um, Next Color Planet, Matsuri, you know, had calls in it, right? It had them, didn't it?"
あの、知ってる？でもね、あの、間違えちゃいました読み仮名。すいません。コーラー
"You know it? But, you know, I got the furigana wrong. Sorry. Cola—"
英語勉強しますね。心地に教えてもらいます。うん、すいません。
"I'll study English. I'll have you teach me comfortably. Yeah, sorry."
ということで、その際に歌った曲は、実は3曲あるんで、ま、書いてあるけどね。
"So, the songs we sang then actually include three songs, well, it's written there though."
これ、どうやって乗っければいいのこれ？これ、どうやって乗ればいいんですか？
"How am I supposed to get on this? How do I get on it?"
ここ、こことか
"Here, here and—"
あ、祭りの身長が足りないんだけど。
"Ah, Matsuri's height isn't enough."
えっとね、「変わらないもの」と「君の知らない物語」と「優しさに包まれたなら」なんですよ。
"Um, 'Kawaranai Mono', 'Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari', and 'Yasashisa ni Tsutsumareta Nara'."
ここ、こういう、あ、小さくなってくれた。ここ、ここ、ここ、ここ、ここまで！ここまでです！緑まで！黄色から緑までです！
"Here, like this—ah, you shrank. Here, here, here, up to here! Up to here! Up to green! From yellow to green!"
正解をお願いします！
"Please give me the correct answer!"
あ、打ち上げられた魚みたいになってしまう。やった！やっと正解！
"Ah, I end up looking like a fish washed ashore. Yay! Finally correct!"
どうもありがとう。パネルさん、ありがとう。あ、大きくなってくれた。よし。正解！
"Thank you so much. Panel-san, thank you. Ah, you made me bigger. Great. Correct!"
ということで、第2問も正解ですね。すいすい問題出してくれてありがとう！
"So, Question 2 is also correct. Thank you Suisei for making the question!"
それじゃあ続いてが、ラスト！お、ラスト！じゃ、これでも全問正解したらディレクターが土下座してくれるっていうのをね、取り付けてみました。
"Well then, next is the last! Oh, last! So if I get all questions right this time, I managed to arrange for the director to do a dogeza for me."
配信外で土下座させるために、あの、頑張ります。その屈辱を味わってほしいんですよ、ディレクターにね。
"To make them do a dogeza off-stream, um, I'll do my best. I want the director to taste that humiliation."
じゃあやっていきましょうか。第最終問題、お願いします！
"So let's do it. Final question, please!"
どどん。
"Ba-dum."
え、白上フブキは夏色祭りの事をどう思ってるでしょう？
"Uh, what does Shirakami Fubuki think of Natsuiro Matsuri?"
祭りでもらってる問題と違うよ！祭りでもらった
That's different from the questions I got! The questions I got...
問題は、祭り、問題だけもらったんだけど、あの……
The questions... I only got the questions, but, um...
あの、Fall Guys、白上は何回目の配信でクリアしたでしょうか？っていう問題が来てたから、
Um, "In how many streams did Shiramaki clear Fall Guys?" That question came up, so
祭り、カンニングしてきたのに！今日、今日カンニングしてきたのに！くそっ！
Matsuri went and cheated! Today! Today she even cheated! Damn it!
くそっ！なんでだよ、白上裏切ったら、お前やったらサプライズ問題じゃねえか！
Damn it! Why, Shiramaki, if you betray me, if it's you, isn't that a surprise question?!
え、これ難しいんだけど、えー？
Eh, this is difficult... Eh?
でもね、普通に考えたらね、青なんよ。青だと思うんよ。
But, you know, normally thinking about it, it's blue. I think it's blue.
祭りはい、うん、カンニング対策とはさすがそういうことか。でもこれ難しくね？どう思ってるでしょ？
Matsuri, yeah, as expected of anti-cheating measures. But isn't this hard? What does she think?
どう思われてんだ。祭り、ちなみに白上のことは、あの、フブキはね、あの、
What does she think of me? By the way, about Shiramaki, Fubuki, um...
みんなをまとめる才能があって、気配りができて、すごいかわいいの、
has the talent to bring everyone together, is considerate, and is super cute...
あのね、祭りごはん食べてるときの白上がすげえ好きなんだよね。超可愛いんだよ。毎回ね、おいしい、おいしいって言いながら食べてくれるわけよ。もう最高だねって言うね、白上の話になってしまいましたけど。
You know, I really love Shiramaki when she's eating. She's super cute. Every time she eats saying "delicious, delicious!" It's just the best, she'd say—well, it turned into talking about Shiramaki.
まあ、でもとっても可愛いお姫様になりたいって言ってるから、お姫様とも思っててほしいし、
Well, but since she says she wants to be a very cute princess, I want people to think of her as a princess, and...
うーん、努力家で優しい子、うーん、どれなんだろ。なんかこれ自分でさ、「実は努力家で優しい子と思われてます」って言うのクソ恥ずかしいんだよな。
Hmm, a hardworking and kind girl... Hmm, which one is it? It's super embarrassing to say yourself, "Actually, people think I'm a hardworking and kind girl."
でもなんか思われてたら嬉しいなって言うと、まあ、可愛い女の子大好き人間は正解。だってそうだから。
But if people thought that, I'd be happy, so... "Loves cute girls" is the correct answer. Because it's true!
可愛い女の子、女、可愛い女の子しか勝たん！って感じですね。
Cute girls, girls, only cute girls can win! That's the vibe.
で、スキップできないのは、最近練習してるんですよ。最近練習してるから、もうできますけどね、まあ今はやんないけど。うーん、悩みどころだけど、
And "can't skip"—I've been practicing recently. Since I've been practicing recently, I can do it now, but I won't do it now. Hmm, it's a dilemma, but...
決めました。祭り決まりました！
I've decided. Matsuri has decided!
ちょっとちっちゃくなってパネル、ちっちゃくなりな！ちっちゃって、もっと、オッケーオッケー。
Get a bit smaller, panel, get smaller! Make it smaller, more, okay, okay.
あ、ちっちゃい、めちゃちっちゃい。
Ah, small, super small.
ここまで！ここは、ここからだ！ここまで！全部！全部！お願いします！
Up to here! Here, from here! Up to here! All of it! All of it! Please!
全部！！やったーー！全部！！やった！やった、欲張りだ！
All of it!! Yay!! All of it!! Yay! Yay, so greedy!
欲張りが大正解！イエーイ！
Greediness is the ultimate correct answer! Yay!
いやこれ以心伝心すぎ？さすがに。以心伝心じゃ、フブキと、これさ、4択クイズ、タ、択じゃないんだよな。選択してないんだよ。
Man, isn't this too telepathic? As expected. Telepathic with Fubuki... and this, it's a 4-choice quiz, wait, it's not choices! She didn't select!
ということで、祭り全部正解でーーす！イエーイ！
And so, Matsuri got them all right!! Yay!
ディレクターさん、聞こえてますか？この配信が終わったあと、土下座してください。
Director-san, can you hear me? After this stream ends, please dogeza (bow in prostration).
ディレクター、これがホロライブだ。ホロライブに入りたいって思ってるそこのキミ、こんな会社です。頑張ってください。
Director, this is Hololive. You out there thinking you want to join Hololive—this is what the company is like. Do your best!
ということで、以上4択祭りのコーナーでした！楽しかった！協力してくれたルーナ、そしてスイスイ、そしてフブキ、ありがとう！サンキュー！サンキュー！
And with that, that concludes the 4-Choice Matsuri corner! It was fun! Thank you to Luna, Suisui, and Fubuki for cooperating! Thank you! Thank you!
ということで、続いてまいりましょうか。続いてのコーナーは、そして「夏色シチュエーション」！しょん、しょん、しょん、しょん、しょん！
And with that, let's move on. The next corner is... "Natsuiro Situation"! Shon, shon, shon, shon, shon!
え、「夏色シチュエーション」ってどんなコーナーなんだろうって思ったそこのキミ！こちらのコーナーはホロライブメンバーにシチュエーションを指定してもらって、そのシチュエーションに合わせて祭りしとすごそう、というコーナーです。
Eh, you out there wondering what kind of corner "Natsuiro Situation" is? In this corner, Hololive members specify a situation, and Matsuri and them spend time together according to that situation!
え、さっそく、あ、さっそくこの方からシチュエーションをいただき、マッスル！
Eh, right away, ah, right away receiving a situation from this person... Muscle!
マッスルって言ってる時点でわかっちゃうけど。
You can already tell just by her saying "Muscle."
え、ノエルからいただきました。白銀ノエル、ありがとう！引っ越してきたお隣さんが最推しのお祭り先輩だった、というシチュエーションからいただきました。ありがとうございます！
Eh, I received it from Noel. Shirogane Noel, thank you! I received it from the situation: "The neighbor who moved in turned out to be my absolute favorite Matsuri-senpai." Thank you very much!
引っ越しだ、最近しましたからね。お隣さんが祭りだったらって、話さ、そう、昨日のね、昨日の夜にあすみおやすってそんときにね、ちょうど話してたよね。なんか、祭りすの、あの、隣の家に
Moving, I did it recently, you know. Talking about "What if my neighbor was Matsuri?" Right, yesterday, last night during Asumioyasu, we were talking about it right then. Like, Matsuri's, um, next door house...
引っ越して…みたいな
Like you just moved in...
話してたよね。
You were talking about it, right?
では、今回は、長船様がありがとうございます。
So, for this time, thank you very much, Osafune-sama.
じゃあ、行きますか。
Shall we go then?
カメラをね、なんかちょっと準備するみたいななので、少々お待ちくださいませ。
We're preparing the camera a bit, so please wait a moment.
出るかな？
Will it appear?
あ、出た。
Ah, it appeared.
あの、今日カメラ持ってくれてるのがね、すごいね、可愛い女の子なんです。可愛い女の子なんですけど
Uhm, the person holding the camera today is a really cute girl. She's a cute girl, but...
だから、今日はこの、女の子をね、ドキドキさせるためにも頑張っていきたいと思います。
So today, I'll do my best to make this girl's heart flutter.
それじゃあちょっと、場面転換しましょう。
Well then, let's do a scene change.
場面転換、出ずら！ゴー！シュイーン、シュイーン！
Scene change... Out of place! Go! Whoosh, whoosh!
マンションやん、普通に。
It's just an ordinary apartment.
ここ、祭りの家です。
This is Matsuri's house.
皆さん、祭りの家へようこそ。
Welcome to Matsuri's house, everyone.
ってことで、じゃあシチュエーション行きますか。
With that said, shall we go to the scenario?
それでは、シチュエーション、スタート！
Well then, scenario, start!
あ、おはようございます。あ、ゴミ捨てですか？
Ah, good morning. Ah, taking out the trash?
あー、ここのゴミ捨て、結構めんどくさいですよね。
Ah, taking out the trash here is quite a hassle, isn't it?
え？あ、祭りのこと知ってる？
Eh? Ah, do you know about Matsuri?
え、こわっ！え、こわっ！
Eh, creepy! Eh, creepy!
めっちゃ怖いんだけど、この人。
This person is super creepy.
宝のとこ、え、あ、なんですか？
Takara's place... Eh, ah, what is it?
はい。
Yes.
あ、え？このあとですか？ごはんですか？え、どこ行くんですか？
Ah, eh? After this? Meals? Eh, where are you going?
焼肉？え？
Yakiniku? Eh?
連れてってくれるんですか？
Will you take me with you?
え、ほんと？ほんと？
Eh, really? Really?
え、じゃあ、行こっかなー！行っちゃおっかなー！
Eh, then I guess I'll go! I might as well go!
焼肉、え、ちなみにどこですか？ジョージ苑？
Yakiniku... eh, by the way, where is it? Jojo-en?
あ、ジョージ苑？
Ah, Jojo-en?
ジョージ苑は、もう行くしかない！
Jojo-en, I have no choice but to go!
早く行きましょう！
Let's hurry and go!
え、早く行きましょうよ。あ、ちょっと待ってください。
Eh, let's hurry up. Ah, wait a minute.
祭りもう、ジョージ苑行くなら、あの、メイクだけちょっとしていくんで。
Matsuri, if we're going to Jojo-en, I'll just do my makeup a bit.
じゃあ、あの、ここで待っててくださいね。それではまたあとで！
So, um, please wait here. See you later!
終わり！
End!
いやー、これはドキドキしたよね！ドキドキした？
Man, that made my heart flutter! Did your heart flutter?
した！した！した！
It did! It did! It did!
チロいって言わないでよ！
Don't call me cheap!
焼肉には釣られてしまうよね。
I get lured in by yakiniku, huh.
最高？最高だってさ！
The best? It's the best, they say!
これ、ノエルが望んだ展開になっているのかしら？どうなんだろうか。
I wonder if this turned out the way Noel wanted? I wonder.
皆さん、ドキドキした人！ドキドキした？別の意味でドキドキするかもしれないよね。
Everyone, who's heart fluttered? Did it flutter? You might be fluttering for a different reason.
俺の財布、大丈夫かな？
Is my wallet okay?
でね、あの、カメラマンをね、まあ、あの、女が、女がっていうか、仲良い女の子がやってくれてるんだけど、ずっとニコニコしてるからね。
And you know, the cameraman, well, a girl—well, not just a girl, a good female friend is doing it, but she's been smiling the whole time.
すごいね、楽しい。
It's really fun.
ありがとう、ドキドキしてくれてる人はいるけど、全肯定じゃねえか！
Thank you, there are people whose hearts are fluttering, but that's total affirmation!
全肯定祭りじゃねえか！
This is a 100% affirmative festival!
ということで、ありがとうございます。ノエル、ありがとね、シチュエーション送ってくれて。
So, thank you very much. Noel, thanks for sending the scenario.
ということで、じゃあ続いていきましょう。続いてのは、ちょっとね、まあ、長い、長いみたいなのですけども。
With that said, let's move on to the next one. The next one is a bit, well, long.
じゃあ、行きましょう！続いてのシチュエーションがこちら！
Well then, let's go! The next scenario is this one!
友人Aからのシチュエーション。お忍びで彼氏彼女まつりと少し遠くに羽を伸ばしに、海が綺麗な島に来た俺。2泊3日のデート最終日、今日で東京に帰る。空港に向かうまであと1時間半。なんとなく名残惜しい海を見ている夕方、午後4時半。
Scenario from Friend A. On a secret trip with my girlfriend Matsuri to spread our wings a bit further away, I came to an island with beautiful seas. The final day of our 3-day, 2-night date, returning to Tokyo today. 1 and a half hours until heading to the airport. Evening, 4:30 PM, looking at the ocean with a somewhat lingering feeling.
気持ち悪っ！
Gross!
ガチオタクみたいなやつやん！
That's like a hardcore otaku!
設定細か！
Detailed settings!
だから、長っ！
So long!
めちゃくちゃ長いいんだけど！
It's insanely long!
いや、でもね、分かりやすいですよ。ポエムみたいで、すごい素敵だと思いますけども。
Well, but you know, it's easy to understand. It's like a poem, I think it's very wonderful.
2泊3日のデートを祭りときみでした。で、今日で東京に帰らないといけないけど名残惜しいねって、海を見ているんですね。
We had a 3-day, 2-night date with Matsuri and you. And today we have to go back to Tokyo, but it's bittersweet, so we're looking at the ocean.
なるほどね。
I see.
分かったよ。やりますか、じゃあ。
I got it. Shall we do it then?
じゃあ、一旦カメラの準備をしますね。カメラ準備、ゴー！いけるかな？あ、いけた、いけた。カメラさん、ありがとうございます。
Well then, let's prepare the camera once. Camera preparation, go! Can we do it? Ah, it worked, it worked. Thank you, cameraman.
ということで、ポエム、Aちゃんの望みを叶えるために、ちょっと真剣にやるわ。真剣にガチでやるね。
So, to fulfill poem A-chan's wish, I'll do it seriously. I'll do it really seriously.
じゃあ、ちょっと場所だけ変えましょうか。場所、チェンジ！
Well then, shall we change location? Location, change!
あ、海だ！
Ah, the ocean!
え、綺麗！綺麗だね。
Ah, it's pretty! It's pretty.
じゃあ、じゃあ、行きますか。
Well then, shall we go?
じゃあ、シチュエーション、よーい、スタート！
Then, scenario, ready, start!
海、綺麗だね。
The ocean is so pretty.
あと1時間半か
Only an hour and a half left, huh.
楽しいよね
Man, that was fun.
祭りね、やりたかったこと1つできなくてさ
There was one thing I wanted to do for the stream that I couldn't...
そう
Yeah.
で、本当はさ、そう、あそこのさ、あの、団子食べたかったんだよ、でさ、時間なかったじゃん？
I actually really wanted to eat those dango over there, you know? But we didn't have time.
また一緒に来てくれる？
Will you come with me again?
なんか、また来れるって思ったら、いっかな、今日は、一緒に帰れるし
Well, thinking I can come back again... I guess it's fine for today, since we're going home together.
あと、東京帰ってからさ、行きたいとこもあるから、またLINEするね
After we get back to Tokyo, there are places I want to go, so I'll message you on LINE.
じゃあ、そろそろ時間だから行こうか
Well, it's about time, so let's get going.
はずい
So embarrassing...
逃げる
I'm running!
はずい、終わり！終わり終わり終わり！終わり終わり！
So embarrassing, it's over! Over, over, over! Over, over!
はずいわ
So embarrassing...
はずい、なんか、はずかしい
So embarrassing, man, how embarrassing.
もう一緒に行かないから、どこにも
No, we're not going anywhere together anymore!
ということで、以上、以上、海辺で1時間半の、なんか、ちょっと長すぎて覚えてないけど
So anyway, that's all for the hour and a half by the ocean... Well, it was a bit too long so I don't really remember, but
2泊3日した、なんか、えーちゃんとの思い出でした
those were my memories of our 3-day, 2-night trip with Ee-chan!
ありがとうございました、あー、緊張したよ、団子食べに行こうな
Thank you very much. Ah, I was so nervous! Let's go eat dango.
団子の、あそこの団子美味しいって有名だったからさ
You know, those dango around there were famous for being delicious.
そして、あ、えーちゃんありがとね
And, ah, Ee-chan thanks!
そして、最後にですね、祭すから、何個、学校、この学校でのシチュエーションを1個だけ募集しようかなって思うのでコメントで、あの、なんか言ってくれると
And finally, from Matsuri... I thought I'd take requests for just one school situation to do here, so if you could leave a comment
こういうシチュエーションが見たい！っていうのを言ってくれると嬉しいぞ
saying something like 'I want to see this kind of situation!', I'd be happy!
おい、頼んだ、おい、なんかありますか？短い感じで、あ、なんか結構できるみたいだから、2、3個できるって、何がいいですか？祭りちゃんに告白して振られる？
Hey, I'm counting on you! Hey, do you have any? Short ones, like, looks like we can do quite a few, about two or three. What do you think? Confessing to Matsuri-chan and getting rejected?
振られたいの？
You want to get rejected?
でもね、よく言われるんだよ、エゴサしてても、なんか、祭りちゃんに告白して振られたいっていうのが出てくるの
But you know, people often say—even when I'm ego-searching—that they want to confess to Matsuri-chan and get rejected.
フルアじゃあ、フルね、祭り、じゃあちょっとカメラさん、お願いします
Reject, huh? Reject, then. Matsuri... alright, camera-san, please.
じゃあ行くよ、シチュエーション、よーい、スタート！
Alright, here we go. Situation, ready, start!
え、明る？BGM？こういう感じ？
Eh, bright? BGM? Like this?
え、どうしたの？
Eh, what's wrong?
なんか、ぼやけてるな
It's kind of blurry.
え、何？え、声小さくて聞こえないんだけど
Eh, what? Eh, your voice is too quiet, I can't hear you.
あー、祭りのこと好きなんだ
Ah, you like Matsuri?
そっか、ま、祭りは無理だけどね、うん、ごめん
I see. Well, Matsuri is out of the question though, yeah, sorry.
なんか、そういう夢で見てなかったわ、逆に、なんか、見られてたんだ、みたいな
I didn't expect to be in that kind of dream... rather, I was the one being watched, or something.
あ、そっか、ごめん、あの、これからの友達として、よろしく、うん、ごめんね、なんか
Ah, I see, sorry. Um, let's get along as friends from now on, yeah, sorry about that.
じゃ、祭り、あのこの後、友達と帰るから。お疲れ、バイバイ！
Well, Matsuri, um, I'm going home with a friend after this. Good work, bye-bye!
どう？どう？
How was that? How was that?
一番傷つく
That hurts the most!
ああー、一番傷つくって言われた
Ahhh, you said that hurts the most!
いや、告白したくなった。いや、そんな、そんな、こんな軽い振り方しないよ、普通はね？普通は
Man, I wanted to confess. No, like, people don't usually reject someone so casually, right? Usually.
でもBGMが軽かったからさ、めっちゃ、テンテンテーン、テンテンテーンみたいなBGMだったからさ
But the BGM was so light, like 'tententeen, tententeen' kind of BGM,
合わせなきゃと思って！合わせなきゃと思って、ちょっと振ったけど、本当だったら、なんか祭りも辛そうな顔をするよ
so I thought I had to match it! I thought I had to match it and rejected you like that, but in reality, Matsuri would probably make a painful face too.
なんか、ゴリゴリ削られた、ごめんね、削ってしまって。ごめんね
I feel totally chipped away... sorry for grinding you down. Sorry.
ごめん、ごめんね、大好きだよ、許して
Sorry, sorry, I love you, forgive me.
じゃあ、次、次、次、次行こう
Well, next, next, next, let's go next.
次のシチュエーション、どうですか皆さん、何かありますか、やってほしいなっていうやつ、なんかありますかね？ある？逆に、フルパターンが見たい、なるほどね、祭りがふられんの？
Next situation, how is it everyone, is there anything you want me to do? Is there anything? Got one? Conversely, you want to see the rejection pattern... I see, Matsuri gets rejected?
祭りが振られるパターンね、じゃあ、今回の、BGMなくしてもらおうか。じゃあちょっとカメラさんのほうにチェンジ
Matsuri gets rejected pattern, huh. Then let's have the BGM removed for this one. Alright, let's switch to the camera-san's side.
BGMなしで行きましょうか。
Shall we go without BGM?
それじゃ行きますよ。
Alright, here we go.
よーい、スタート！
Ready... Start!
あのさ... えっと...
Um... you see... uh...
祭りね...
Matsuri, y'know...
君のこと... 好きなんだよね。
I like... you, you know.
付き合ってほしいんだけど。
I want you to go out with me.
え？
Eh?
あ...
Ah...
彼女いるんだ。そっか。
You have a girlfriend. I see.
ごめんね、なんか... 知らなかったからさ。その... うん。
Sorry, y'know... I didn't know. So... yeah.
関わらない方がいい...
It's better not to get involved...
でも祭り好きだからさ... ずっと好きだから。
But Matsuri likes you... she's always liked you.
もし... 祭りいいなって思ったらまた声かけてね。
If you... think Matsuri's okay, hit me up again, okay?
じゃ。
Well then.
どうだ！どうだ！
How's that! How's that!
どうですか？
How is it?
どうだった？良い？良かったかな？
How was it? Good? Was it good?
すぐ彼女と別れるやめてもろて！
Quit breaking up with your girlfriend right away!
大切にしてをもろて彼女のことは！
Treat your girlfriend right!
まあね、まあ祭りは諦めの悪い女なんでね、一回ね、あの... あれですよ、いいなと思ったらもう... もうあれだから、離さないからね、君のことをね、よろしくお願いします。
Well, y'know, Matsuri is a woman who doesn't give up easily...
別れてくるわ。
"I'll go break up with her."
やめて！大切にして彼女のことを！大切にしてあげて！うん、彼女ふたりでもいいやん？
Stop! Treat your girlfriend right! Cherish her! Yeah, what's wrong with having two girlfriends?
独処じゃねえか、ほんとやめとけ！一番無理なタイプ！一番無理、本当に！
That's solitary confinement, seriously stop it! That's the worst type! The absolute worst, really!
じゃあ次ラストで行きますか？次最後。
Shall we go with the last one next? Next is the final one.
なんかいい感じのドキドキするやつやりたいたくない？なんかふりふられなんだけど。
Don't you want to do some heart-pumping kind of scenario? It's like being rejected or dumped.
ふりふられ辛くない？もっとなんかさ、
Isn't getting dumped or rejected painful?
アマずっぱい青春のようなやつをやりたいなあ。ないかない？
I want to do something more bittersweet and youth-like. Isn't there any?
なんならガチ恋距離とかもできちゃうからさ、なあ。
We could even get super close-up like 'gachikoi' distance, y'know.
どうなのがいい？壁ドンされたい。
What kind do you want? I want a 'kabe-don'.
祭りがする側？壁ドン？は、壁ドンですか？おー、なるほどね。
Matsuri's the one doing it? A kabe-don? Huh, a kabe-don? Oh, I see.
壁ドンしてみるわ。
I'll try doing a kabe-don.
壁ドンするね。
I'll do a kabe-don.
じゃあ、シチュエーションは、こうしよ？だから、もう... あの...
Well then, for the scenario, let's do this. So, um...
どうしようかな？どうしようかな？君に彼女がいて祭りが略奪するパターンで行くわ。
What should I do? We'll go with the pattern where you have a girlfriend and Matsuri steals you away.
ちょっと待って、祭り腕大丈夫そう？
Wait a minute, is Matsuri's arm alright?
じゃあ、行きますか？行きます。略奪はします。
Well then, shall we go? Let's go. I will steal you away.
あ、なんか時間もらえれば壁準備するって。
Ah, they say if they get time, they'll prepare a wall.
壁準備しますって何？なんだろう、るしあのおっぱいが出てくるみたいなそういうことかな？
What do they mean by 'preparing a wall'? I wonder, is it like Rushia's boobs coming out or something?
壁が準備されるみたいなんで、少々お待ちください。
It seems a wall is being prepared, so please wait a moment.
さっきの、あの... 祭り振られたけど諦められなかったパターンで行くわ。
We'll go with the pattern where Matsuri got rejected earlier, but couldn't give up.
壁準備しますって今、天の声が聞こえてきてるぞ、どういうこと？
A voice from the heavens just said 'preparing a wall', what does that mean?
えーちゃんが来てくんのかな？えーちゃんが... えーちゃんを...
Will A-chan come? A-chan... A-chan...
るしあのパネルとかえーちゃんのパネルとかシオンのパネルがトントンってたすかもしれない。
Rushia's panel, A-chan's panel, or Shion's panel might just pop up with a thud.
ていうことで壁が壁呼んだら苦しそうなので行きます。
So since calling a wall might be painful, let's go.
行くよ！壁！あ、本当に壁だ！ただの壁だ！なんだろう、るしあじゃないのか？
Here I go! Wall! Ah, it really is a wall! Just a wall! I wonder, isn't it Rushia?
じゃあ行きますか。カメラさんよさげかな？
Shall we go then? Is the camera angle okay?
ちょっと斜めにから... なんかさ、壁ドンしてるのをさ、見てんの変だから、じゃあカメラさんにちゃんとやりますね。
From a bit sideways... seeing someone doing a kabe-don looks weird, so I'll do it properly for the camera.
じゃあ、カメラ位置移動しても大丈夫ですか？
Well, is it okay to move the camera position?
へい！
Hey!
や、これ壁よいしても意味ないやつじゃね？壁よいしても意味なかったね。まあ、壁あるよっていう心でみてん。
Wait, isn't this a useless wall prep? Preparing a wall was pointless. Well, just watch with the mindset that there's a wall.
じゃ行きますよ。
Alright, here we go.
BGM切ってもらって。
Please turn off the BGM.
じゃ行きます。
Here I go.
よーい、スタート！
Ready, start!
祭りにすれば…だめ？
If it's Matsuri... no good?
恥ず…
Embarrassing...
恥ずかしい！恥ずかし、恥ずかしいわ、今
So embarrassing, so embarrassing, right now!
今！
Right now!
ねぇ、恥ずかしくないでね？ねぇ
Hey, don't be embarrassed, hey, hey!
やめて本当にさ、カメラさんとじゃれてる、今
Stop it, seriously, messing around with the camera right now.
あ、うまっちゃった。祭りがあ、ね、祭りやりたいことがあるんだけど、見てて
Ah, I missed it. Matsuri has something she wants to do, so watch.
祭りが壁になるんだよ
Matsuri is going to become a wall!
撮られた人はソファになってましたが、祭りは壁になります
The person who was filmed became a sofa, but Matsuri will become a wall.
こういうの、あるよね？こういうの
You know, things like this exist, right? Things like this.
あ、これだめかな、怒られるわ
Ah, is this no good? I'll get yelled at.
やめましょう！壁を消そう
Let's stop! Let's erase the wall.
ちょっとこれ、怒られそう
Wait, I might get yelled at for this.
さようなら壁、バイバイ
Goodbye wall, bye-bye!
怒られそうだったわ
I looked like I was going to get yelled at.
ということでね、すごい楽しかったでしょ？
So anyway, it was a lot of fun, right?
ありがとう！シチュエーションを送ってくれた、そこの君も、そこの君も、そこの君もありがとうございますね
Thank you! To you, you, and you who sent in the scenarios, thank you very much!
ありがとう、そしてカメラさんもありがとう
Thank you, and thank you to the camera person too!
はい、ピコってお辞儀してたわ
Yes, I was bowing with a "piko".
ということで、ええと、ちょっとはね、夏の思い出作れましたか？
So, um, were you able to make a bit of summer memories?
みんな夏、もう名残り惜しくなくなった？秋も祭りときょろしくね？
Is everyone not missing summer anymore? Please look forward to autumn with Matsuri too!
ということで、最後は、もうこの時間、もう最後の時間になりました
So, finally, it's already this time, it has become the final time.
それでは、最後は、ミニライブがあります
Well then, finally, there will be a mini live.
ちょっとちょっと着替えてくるので、皆さん、祭り配信前に
I'm going to go change real quick, so everyone, before Matsuri's stream,
頑張って、あの、ストレッチとか運動してたんです
I worked hard doing, um, stretching and exercising.
そちらの映像をご覧下さい。着替えてくるからちょっと待っててね、行ってきます！
Please take a look at that footage. Wait a second while I go change, I'll be right back!
測定します！
Measuring!
1、2、3、4
1, 2, 3, 4
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
たーん！
Ta-da!
なんかもう一回やれって言われました
They told me to do it one more time.
他にできることは、あ、スキップの練習を最近しました
Other things I can do, ah, I recently practiced skipping.
ちょっと上達したね、バイバイ
I improved a bit, bye-bye!
うまくなったな
I got better.
測定します！
Measuring!
1、2、3、4
1, 2, 3, 4
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
たーん！
Ta-da!
なんかもう一回やれって言われました
They told me to do it one more time.
他にできることは、あ、スキップの練習を最近しました
Other things I can do, ah, I recently practiced skipping.
ちょっと上達したね、バイバイ
I improved a bit, bye-bye!
うまくなったな
I got better.
測定します！
Measuring!
1、2、3、4
1, 2, 3, 4
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
たーん！
Ta-da!
なんかもう一回やれって言われました
They told me to do it one more time.
他にできることは、あ、スキップの練習を最近しました
Other things I can do, ah, I recently practiced skipping.
ちょっと上達したね、バイバイ
I improved a bit, bye-bye!
うまくなったな
I got better.
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった投げキスで”
My repayment is "a loving flying kiss"!
気のせいじゃない
It's not just my imagination.
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
Repaying you with "a love-filled flying kiss!"
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not my imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って恋しちゃってください！
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever it takes,
ＮＧ無しで体当たり挑戦
Taking on any challenge head-on with no limits!
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
The anti comments I found from ego-searching—
ぶざけんな…誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me... I know that better than anyone!
でも大丈夫ステージ(ここ)に立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand on this stage, everyone is here!
(いくよ！)
Let's go!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
Repaying you with "a love-filled flying kiss!"
狂いそう！もっと！夢を見せて！もっと！
Driving me wild! More! Show me dreams! More!
楽しんでいて愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this love-filled special night!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them!
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
A scandal is still too early, but—
裏切りません！宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I'll make that declaration!
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment!
ぶざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with my real skills!
だから辞めない負けず嫌い私はいる
That's why I won't quit, my competitive self is right here!
(いくよ！)
Let's go!
ぶっかまして！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Knock it out of the park! More! Sweat it out! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもったmonaビームで”
Repaying you "with a love-filled Mona beam!"
大歓声！もっと！まだまだね？ねえ？もっと！
Huge cheers! More! Is that all? Hey? More!
受け止めてね愛のこもったわがままソング
Please accept this love-filled selfish song!
はぁ…終わりが近づく寂しいね
Ah... the end is drawing near, how lonely...
楽しいのに泣きそうだよ
Even though it's so fun, I'm about to cry.
次も次もまた会えるよね？
We'll meet again and again, right?
(約束！)
Promise!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
And even the callous words of someone else—
必要なんだ必要なんだ
They're all necessary, they're all necessary!
強くなろう
Let's become stronger!
好きに叫べ！もっと！楽しんだもん勝ち！もっと！
Shout out your love! More! The ones who have fun win! More!
忘れしないで特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, so this can become a special day!
ともに歌おうずっと！ともに歩もうずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
愛の言葉はとびっきりのL・O・V・E
Words of love are an exceptional L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
Repaying you with "a love-filled flying kiss!"
狂いそう！もっと！夢を見せて！もっと！
Driving me wild! More! Show me dreams! More!
楽しんでいて愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
楽しみにしてたのに泣きそうだよ
Even though I was looking forward to it, I'm about to cry.
次も次もまた会えるよね？
We'll meet again and again, right?
約束！
Promise!
みんなー！５０万人ほんとにありがとう！
Everyone~! Thank you so much for 500k!
これからも１００万人に行くまで走り続けるからよろしくね！
I'll keep running until we reach 1 million, so please keep supporting me!
優しさに触れている言葉も
Words touching upon kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
And even the callous words of someone else—
必要なんだ必要なんだ
They're all necessary, they're all necessary!
強くなろう
Let's become stronger!
好きに叫べ！もっと！楽しんだもん勝ち！もっと！
Shout out your love! More! The ones who have fun win! More!
忘れしないで特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, so this can become a special day!
ともに歌おうずっと！ともに歩もうずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
愛の言葉はとびっきりのL・O・V・E
Words of love are an exceptional L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛のこもった投げキスで”
Repaying you with "a love-filled flying kiss!"
狂いそう！もっと！夢を見せて！もっと！
Driving me wild! More! Show me dreams! More!
楽しんでいて愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
Enjoy this love-filled special night!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them!
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
A scandal is still too early, but—
裏切りません！宣言しときます
I won't betray you! I'll make that declaration!
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment!
ぶざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with my real skills!
だから辞めない負けず嫌い私はいる
That's why I won't quit, my competitive self is right here!
ぶっかまして！もっと！
Knock it out of the park! More!
汗をかいて！もっと！
Sweat it out! More!
恩返しは…ファンサしちゃうぞ！
Repaying you with... fan service!
ありがとうございましたー！ファンサでしたー！
Thank you very much~! That was Fansa!
はい、ということでありがとうございました。改めまして、ファンサでしたー！
Yes, so thank you very much. Once again, that was Fansa!
いやね、この曲はね、マジで好きなの。あの、あくあちゃんのさ、ライブでもさ、歌ってたじゃん。マジでガチ泣きしちゃって。本当にね、もうなんかこの曲は
Man, I seriously love this song. You know, Aqua-chan sang it at her live too, right? I seriously cried real tears. Really, you know, this song is...
ま、いろんなね、推してる方がいると思うんですけど、どんなね、アイドル、どんなVTuberに合わせてもね、本当にこういろんな思い出が蘇る素敵な曲だなあって思いますね。マジで好き。本当に好き。神曲だと思います。
Well, I think there are people stanning various people, but no matter what idol or VTuber you match it with, I think it's a wonderful song that brings back so many memories. I seriously love it. I truly love it. I think it's a god-tier song.
ありがとうございます。まつりといえばって言ってくださる方も多いので、本当にね、それが嬉しいですね。ありがとうございます。ということで、ここでね、ま、あの、告知があります。
Thank you very much. There are many people who say "Speaking of Matsuri," so I'm really happy about that. Thank you very much. And so, right here, um, there is an announcement.
みんなに嬉しい告知だとまつりも嬉しいです。ということでね、あの、あの、行きますか？まず一つ目、行きますよ。こちら、どどーん！
If it's a happy announcement for everyone, Matsuri is happy too. And so, um, shall we go? First one, here we go. Ta-da!
夏色まつり 登録50万人記念グッズ アクリルキーホルダー＆ステッカー
[Natsuiro Matsuri 500k Subscribers Commemorative Goods: Acrylic Keychain & Sticker]
で、このあと21時からですね、
So, starting at 21:00 tonight,
あの、販売します。ブースさんにて販売します。
um, we'll be selling them at the booth.
概要欄の方に、えっと、配信が終わったあとに更新されますので、
In the description box, um, it will be updated after the stream ends,
配信が終わったらね、ポチッて押してみたらね、ブースさんに飛べると思いますので、
so once it's over, if you tap it, you should be able to go to the booth,
よろしくお願いいたします。こちらはいつもお世話になってますイオカン先生にね、描いていただきましたよ。
so please check it out. They were drawn by Iokan-sensei, who always takes great care of us.
あの、例えば、ま祭とかね、あと祭りのロリ祭りとかね、
Um, for example, Mama-matsuri, or festival loli-matsuri,
を描いてくださっている方が、描いてくださいました。50万人記念、ぜひ、祭りも買うので一緒に お揃いにしてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
the person who draws those drew these. To commemorate 500k subscribers, I'd be so happy if you bought them to match with me!
よろしくお願いします。めっちゃかわいいやろ。5ってやってるの。5ってやってますのでね。あ、5ってやってます。やってますのでよろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to it. Aren't they super cute? I'm doing a "5". So please look forward to it!
はい。そしてね、もう一つありますよ。もうこちらTwitterの方で告知されておりますが、
Yes. And there's one more thing. It's already been announced on Twitter, but...
ドン、でますかね？はい、こちら、
Ta-da! Will it appear? Yes, right here.
ええとですね、ブラウンダストという、あの、ゲームの方に祭りが出演、
Um, Matsuri will be appearing in a game called Brown Dust,
そしていただくことになりました。ユリセア役、こちら27歳のお姉ちゃんなんだよ。
playing the role of Yuriessa, a 27-year-old big sister!
えっ！27歳のお姉さんを祭りがやるんですかって、この、はい、務めさせていただきました。
Eh?! Matsuri is playing a 27-year-old big sister?! Yes, I got to take on this role!
そしてギュンターというキャラクターがいて、そちらはなんとね、モコさんがやっているみたいですよ。
And there's a character named Gunther, who apparently is voiced by Moko-san!
それの、えっと協力者、なので並んで使ってください。
And since she's his helper, please use us side by side!
はい。なんかちょっとね、意外なところでコラボができているみたいな感じになっておりますけどもね。はい。
Yeah. It feels like we're collaborating in a rather unexpected place. Yes!
ぜひ、あの皆さん使ってくれたら嬉しいなと思います。祭りあの、すごい意外なボイスをしています。
I'd be so happy if everyone uses them. Matsuri does a surprisingly unique voice for this.
本当ににかっこいいお姉さんっていう感じで、今まで出したことないような声をしているので、興味がある方はぜひね、Twitterとかでもあの告知しているので、9月3日かなに、えっと、アプデが入って実装されるので、ぜひよろしくお願いいたします。はい、気になる方はブラウンダストで検索、検索！
It's like a really cool big sister voice, a kind of voice I've never done before. So if you're interested, please check out the announcement on Twitter. The update drops around September 3rd and it gets implemented, so please check it out! Yep, if you're curious, search "Brown Dust", search!
とゆことで、みなさんね、あの、改めて50万人ありがとうございます。
And with that, everyone, thank you once again for 500,000 subscribers!
あの、こうやってさ、あの祭りずっと声優やりたい、CDやりたいて言ってて、こうやって夢を叶えれたのもね、みんながこう応援してくれてるおかげだなって本当にね、日々思っております。
Um, ever since I said I wanted to do voice acting and release CDs, being able to fulfill these dreams is truly thanks to everyone's support. I feel that every single day.
そしてね、ホロライブも新しいご期生がね、増えて、またコラボができるようになったらね、あの解禁、解禁されたらどんどんしていきたいと思うので、その時はね、あの、よろしくお願いします。ぜひ見てください。
And as Hololive grows with new 5th-gen members, once collabs are unlocked, I want to do more and more of them. When that time comes, please look forward to it and make sure to watch!
あの、祭り含めホロライブを今後ともよろしくね、みんな！というこことで、
Please continue to support Hololive, including Matsuri, everyone! With that said,
最後は、祭り実はこの曲歌ったことないんじゃないか、歌ったことあったかな？ほぼ歌ったことないと思うんで、ちょっとレアな曲をね、歌いますよ。それでは、この曲で最後で終わっていきましょう。聞いてください、「キラメキラライダー」
finally, Matsuri has actually probably never sung this song before—wait, have I sung it before? I think I've almost never sung it, so I'll sing a rather rare song. Well then, let's end with this song. Please listen to "Kirameki Rider".
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make the newborn excitement echo!
最高の時間最高の中へ、もっとキラメキにのって
Head into the greatest time, into the greatest moment, riding the sparkle!
覚えてるかな最初の歌
Do you remember our very first song?
私の声は震えていた
My voice was trembling.
あの日から続く未来は、みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
The future continuing from that day is today, which we grasped together with everyone.
もっともっともっともっと加速するハート
Accelerate our hearts more, more, more, more!
いくよどこまでも準備はOK？
Let's go anywhere, are you ready?
開け夢の扉を
Open the door of dreams!
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう、最高の時間最高の中へ
Let's make the newborn excitement echo, into the greatest time, into the greatest moment!
ここにいるよ見つけてくれたから、君に逢いたくてやってきたんだみんなで歌おう終わらないメロディ
I'm right here because you found me. I came here wanting to see you, so let's all sing an endless melody!
キラメキにのって
Riding the sparkle!
届いてるかな
Is it reaching you?
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn excitement echo out,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and the best friends!
キラメキに乗って☆
Riding on the sparkle—☆
(イェーイ!)
(Yeah!)
覚えているかな? 最初の歌
Do you remember? Our very first song
(懐かしいね) 私の声が震えていた
(Ah, those memories) My voice was shaking
(ほんの少し) あの日から続く
(Just a little bit) The future continuing
未来は みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
from that day is today, grasped together with everyone!
もっともっともっともっと加速するハート (一緒に)
Accelerating more and more and more and more—our hearts (Together!)
行くよどこまでも (are you ready?)
Let's go anywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK?
Is your preparation OK?
ひらけ!夢のトビラを (一、二、三)
Open up! The door of dreams (One, two, three)
(キラメキラライダー)
(Kirameki Rider)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn excitement echo out,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and the best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I came here wanting to see you, so let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って
Riding on the sparkle of an endless melody—
届いているかな? 私の声
Can you hear it? My voice,
(ハッキリと) 届けたいのは 君に笑顔
(Clearly) wanting to reach you with a smile
(そのスマイル) 理想の遠さに悔しくて
(That smile) Frustrated by how distant my ideals were,
みんなで泣き笑ったね
we cried and laughed together.
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっと全て抱きしめて (一緒に)
Holding everything tightly, tightly, tightly, tightly— (Together!)
行こうどこまでも (are you ready?)
Let's go anywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK?
Is your preparation OK?
すすめ!希望の道を (一、二、三)
Advance! Down the path of hope (One, two, three)
(キラメキラライダー)
(Kirameki Rider)
好きな気持ちカラフルに奏でたいんだ
I want to play my feelings colorfully,
最高の場所 最高のみんなと
in the best place, with the best people.
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm right here, this is no illusion.
君の心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart is dyed in happiness,
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキ纏って
layering our harmonies, wrapped in a sparkle.
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing—
そんな願いわがままでもいいでしょ?
Is it okay if such a wish is a bit selfish?
だって楽しすぎてもう止まらない
Because I'm having too much fun to stop now!
輝くステージでもっともっと (お願い!) ずっと (オー!) (イェーイ!)
On this shining stage, more and more— (Please!) forever— (Oh!) (Yeah!)
嬉しい楽しい愛しいだけじゃ語れない
It can't be expressed by just happy, fun, or beloved—
今も今もある悩みはあるけど
though there are still worries even now,
ここにいるよ 私ここにいるよ
I'm right here, I'm right here!
君と同じ世界を見つめて (行くよ?) (キラメキラライダー)
Gazing at the same world as you (Let's go?) (Kirameki Rider)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn excitement echo out,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and the best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう (せーのっ!)
I came here wanting to see you, so let's sing together! (Ready, set!)
終わらないメロディー キラメキに乗って
Riding on the sparkle of an endless melody—
キラメキ纏って (イェーイ!)
Wrapped in a sparkle! (Yeah!)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn excitement echo out,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best times and the best friends!
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me.
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう (せーのっ!)
I came here wanting to see you, so let's sing together! (Ready, set!)
終わらないメロディー
An endless melody,
キラメキに乗って
riding on the sparkle,
キラメキ纏って
wrapped in a sparkle,
(イェーイ!)
(Yeah!)
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
最高だぞ！
You guys are the best!
お祭り！わっしょーい！
Matsuri! Wasshoi!
まつりす
Matsurisu
それは、夏色まつりを愛するもの
Those who love Natsuiro Matsuri
いろんなまつりすがいる
There are all kinds of matsurisu
絵が描けるまつりす
Matsurisu who can draw
音楽ができるまつりす
Matsurisu who can make music
いつも見守ってるまつりす
Matsurisu who are always watching over her
出来ることは違うけれど 愛する気持ちは同じ
Though what we can do differs, our love is the same
そしてそのまつりす達がどんどん増えていく
And those matsurisu keep growing and growing
50,000人が集まったとき、3Dになれた
When 50,000 people gathered, she became 3D
180,000人が集まったとき、アトレでコラボをした
When 180,000 people gathered, she collaborated with Atre
280,000人が集まったとき、テレビに出れた
When 280,000 people gathered, she appeared on TV
440,000人が集まったとき、念願のドーナッツコラボができた
When 440,000 people gathered, her dream donut collaboration happened
まつりちゃんの頑張りが認められてたくさんのまつりすが集まってきた
Recognizing Matsuri-chan's hard work, many matsurisu gathered
まつりちゃんの頑張りが報われるようにたくさんのまつりすが応援してきた
Many matsurisu supported her so that her hard work would be rewarded
まつりちゃんのやりたいことが叶うように まつりちゃんの夢が叶うように
So that Matsuri-chan's wishes and dreams come true
まつりちゃんの夢が叶うように
So that Matsuri-chan's dream comes true,
一人一人のちからは小さいけれど
Each person's power is small, but
50万人も集まれば きっと…
if 500,000 people gather, surely...
50万人 本当にありがとう！
500,000 people, thank you so much!
50万 3D記念配信
500K Subscribers 3D Commemorative Stream